### **CESAR KYLE CASIL**

# Software Developer

Santa Clara, CA 95054 | cesarkylecasil@gmail.com

github.com/ccasil | linkedin.com/in/ckcasil | cesarkylecasil.pink

### **SUMMARY**

I am a Computer Science major practicing full stack development in Python, iOS, and MEAN (MongoDB, Express.js, Angular, Node.js) I have experience in working with small teams using agile software programming. My primary goal is to contribute my passion for programming towards a companies' vision while expanding on my technical skills.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **University of California, Santa Cruz**

Mar 2019

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

### Coding Dojo, Silicon Valley

Apr 2018

- Certificate of Completion, Full Stack Developer: Python, iOS, and MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js) stack development
  - Web development bootcamp specializing in front-end fundamentals as well as three full stacks. Dedicated over 1200+ hours of coding
    experience, including the ability to deploy a full website from client to server to database.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

 $\textbf{Programming Languages:} \ \, \text{JavaScript (ES6)/TypeScript, Swift 4, Python, LAT}_{E}X$ 

Front-End: HTML, CSS, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, JSON, HTTP Request/Response

Database: SQL (MySQL, SQLite), NoSQL (MongoDB), Mongoose.js, Django ORM, Core Data, CRUD operations

Frameworks & Libraries: Angular, React, Node.js, Socket.IO, Express.js, Django, Flask

Development Tools: Git, Microsoft Visual Studio, Xcode, Amazon Web Services (EC2), NGINX, Postman, Node Package Manager (NPM)

Miscellaneous: Agile Scrum Methodology, Algorithms and Data Structures, Software Deployment (AWS), RESTful Architecture/API, Object Oriented

Programming (OOP), Model View Controller (MVC), Microsoft Office

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Web Developer, Love Changing the World, Inc., San Jose, CA

Jun 2018 - Present

- Managed a small team to work with client, LCTW, to create a website for their non-profit organization
- Guests to website can view current and past events held by organization as well as sign up to be a volunteer or sponsor
- Supporters may donate to the organization via PayPal and receive various items of clothing as gifts depending on donation amount
- Technologies Used: React, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Google Maps API, PayPal API, Bootstrap

# Research Intern, MissionU, San Francisco, CA

Mar 2017 - May 2017

- Collaborated in a small team to present a roadshow plan to reach out to local schools and community centers for brand launch
- Drafted 4 research documents from various sources that suggest 1.3 million new job postings in 2020 with skills in data science and analytics
- Curated 4 excel spreadsheets containing 151 subject matter experts, employer partner leads, and various professors to gain input on MissionU's curriculum for the data analyst program

## Android Developer Intern, Garcon LLC, Santa Clara, CA

Sept 2016 - Dec 2016

- Programmed Garcon's Android application using Android Studio and Java during early stages
- Rewrote the UI layout as well as updated deprecated code

## **PROJECTS**

# **Gym Log** — github.com/ccasil/GymLog

Apr 2018

- Personal iOS application to aid in daily workout programs. Includes a user profile, kg/lb conversion calculator, and a log of main lifts.
- Technologies Used: Xcode, Swift, Core Data, Auto Layout

### Dojo Attendance Tracker — github.com/ccasil/geo hack

Mar 2018

- iOS application that records the amount of time spent inside Coding Dojo as well as the time spent outside; can be expanded into an attendance tracker for Coding Dojo.
- Technologies Used: Xcode, Swift, Core Location, Map Kit, AV Foundation, Core Data, Auto Layout

# Baskin Robbins Birthday 31 — github.com/ccasil/BRB31

Feb 2018

- Web application tailored to Baskin Robbins fans. Allows the user to view all flavor descriptions to be added as a favorite.
- Technologies Used: Python, Django, SQLite3, Google Maps JavaScript API, Bcrypt, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Object Relational Mapping (ORM), Object Oriented Programming (OOP)

#### **LEADERSHIP POSITIONS & AFFILIATIONS**

### Lambda Phi Epsilon, Santa Cruz, CA